(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T18:29:30.220209",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ああ、他人事みたいな夜だ
Ah, it's a night that feels like someone else's business
ばら撒いた星だけがキラリ澄んでいる
Only the scattered stars are clear and serene
そんなに綺麗にはなれないや
I can't become that pretty
それでも今夜、往くための歌
Still, this is a song to guide me through tonight
ああ、ほんの小さな夜だ
Ah, it's just such a small night
寝るには早く、夜明けはまだ遠く
Too early to sleep, and dawn is still far away
憧れるには遠く、挫けるにはまだ早いな
Too late to yearn, and still too early to give up
言葉はいつまでも下手だよ
Words are always clumsy
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only sighs get better
傷付く度、違う生き物と知るよ
Every time I get hurt, I learn I am a different creature
いつだって闇で迷子
Always a lost child in the dark
明けない夜があったなら
If there were a night that never breaks
このまま溶けて消えたいや
I'd want to melt and disappear just like this
明けない夜があったって
Even if there were a night that never breaks
私は
I...
煌めく星になれなくて良い
Don't need to become a sparkling star
ああ、本日は閉店です
Ah, business is closed for today too
どうにかこうにか一日
Hanging on somehow for the day
ひっそりこっそり良く頑張り
Doing my best quietly and secretly
何かは残せたのでしょうか？
Did I leave anything behind?
希望的だ 刹那的だ
Optimistic, ephemeral,
楽観的だ でも
Optimistic, but
きっと美しいよ
Surely it is beautiful
言葉はいつまでも下手だよ
Words are always clumsy
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only sighs get better
傷付いて、違う生き物と知って
Knowing that when hurt, I am a different creature
それでも精一杯歌うよ
Still, I will sing with all my might
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there was a night I wanted to cry
笑えない夜があったなら
If there was a night I couldn't smile
溶けて消えて無くなって
Melting away and disappearing
もう一度ゼロから始めよう
Let's start over from zero once again
明日のことはわからないや
I don't know about tomorrow
昨日のことも知らないや
I don't know about yesterday either
明けない夜があったって
Even if there was a night that never breaks
私は
I...
煌めく星になれなくて良い
Don't need to become a sparkling star
きっと答えは もう随分前から出ていた
Surely the answer was clear long ago,
嫉妬、後悔が起因して 鉛のように重い僕の身体
sparked by jealousy and regret, my body is heavy as lead.
ただ僕は透明でありたかった
I just wanted to be transparent.
好意猛威 狂気に変わって
Affection and fury turned into madness,
生も命も精巧だし 本当は単純でいいのに
life and existence are intricate, though it should be simple.
君を貫いて 等価交換しよう
Let's pierce through you in an equivalent exchange.
散りばめられた 甘言さえ愛おしい
Even the scattered sweet words are endearing.
染まらないで 完璧でいてほしいから
Don't let yourself be tainted, I want you to stay perfect.
僕は透明でいるよ 美しい恋にしよう
I will remain transparent, let's make it a beautiful love.
ただ僕は透明でありたかった
I just wanted to be transparent.
脳に一人 こびりついて
Clinging alone inside my brain,
どうして？君はまだ汚れてなんかないんだ!
Why? You aren't tainted at all yet!
亜麻色の髪なびかせて いつまでも少女のままで
Let your flaxen hair flutter, staying a young girl forever.
狂おしいんだ もう戻れない夜に
It's maddening, into a night we can never return to.
僕はまだ囚われたまま べたべたに色を塗り返す
I remain trapped, repainting colors stickily over and over.
自己完結に縋り付くから、どうか――
Clinging to self-containment, please...
君を貫いてよ
Pierce through me...
「このままでいいの？本当に？」
"Is this fine as it is? Really?"
そんな顔するなよ
Don't make that face.
君が「染まりたい」と願ったから
Because you wished to be "tainted"—
僕らはここで終わりだ 美しい君だけが...
Our story ends here, only you, so beautiful...
君を貫いて 等価交換しよう
Let's pierce through you in an equivalent exchange.
散り際の朱 鮮烈さに目が眩み
Blinded by the vivid brilliance at the moment of falling,
染まらないよ 完璧がまた見たいから
I won't let it taint, because I want to see perfection once more.
僕は透明を貫くよ 美しい恋にしよう
I will pierce through transparency, let's make it a beautiful love.
話せないから
Because I cannot speak...
君を繋ぐ空の星が1つ音を立てても
Even if a single star in the sky connecting you makes a sound,
どれも同じ雨に濡れた夢ばかり
they are all just dreams drenched in the same rain.
乾くだけの光 相手をなぞる答えに疲れた
Light that only dries, tired of answers tracing others.
繰り返す陽の無い夜明けに崩れた朝
A morning that crumbled into a repetitive sunless dawn.
捕まえたdaydream
A captured daydream,
出遅れたストーリーと栄光が
lagging stories and glory...
どこへ叫び歌えても
no matter where I shout and sing,
荒れたトンネル声もくぐれない
my voice cannot pass through the rough tunnel.
だからサイレンス灯すためと
That's why, to ignite the silence,
外とパズルのようにハマるピースが必要としても
even if a matching piece like an external puzzle is needed,
影もない偽りと同じだ
it's just like a sham without a shadow.
捨て去られ並ぶだけの賞
Prizes just lined up, discarded.
箱の中に揃えた棘立
Thorny plants gathered in a box,
順番待ちさらし誤魔化しめのゴール
a goal exposed waiting for its turn, deceitful.
Don't be above your daydream
角が取れたvision
A vision stripped of its edges.
君の夢が横で外れても
Even if your dream strays beside me,
僕は歌い橋をかけよう
I will sing and build a bridge.
だからサイレンス鳴らすためと どこまでも片側に沿ったリズム
So that silence echoes, a rhythm hugging one side all the way.
過ぎた街並みは終わりの愛と遠くへ
The passing cityscape goes far away with a final love.
伝えられない歪みかけのイメージに
To a distorted image I cannot convey,
目が覚めた抵抗
awakening resistance,
型落ちの衝動
outdated impulse.
砕けたcry & dream
Shattered cry & dream,
扉だけの理想
ideal of mere doors.
街が雑音に溺れはしゃいでも
Even if the city drowns and frolics in noise,
僕は歌い舵を捨てよう
I will sing and throw away the rudder.
だからサイレンス響くためと
So that silence resonates...
君を繋ぐ空の星が1つ音を立てても
Even if the stars in the sky that connect you make a single sound,
どれも同じ雨に濡れた夢ばかり 乾くだけの光
all dreams drenched in the same rain, a light that merely dries,
相手をなぞる答えに疲れた 繰り返す陽の無い夜明けに崩れた朝
tired of tracing answers, a morning shattered in a sunless dawn.
捕まえたdaydream 出遅れたストーリーと栄光が どこへ叫び叫んでいても
A caught daydream, lagging story and glory, no matter where they shout and cry out,
荒れたトンネル声もくぐれない だからサイレン 燈すためと
the voice can't pass through the ruined tunnel, so a siren to ignite it.
外とパズルのようにハマるピースが必要としても 影もない偽りと同じだ 捨て去り並ぶだけの賞
Even if an outside puzzle piece is needed, it's just like a fake without a shadow, a prize just tossed in a line.
箱の中に揃えた蒔立 順番待ちらしき 誤魔化し化のゴール
Sprouts gathered inside a box, waiting their turn for a deceptive goal.
Don't be above your daydream 角が取れたvision 君の夢が横で外れても
Don't be above your daydream, vision with smoothed edges, even if your dream deviates beside you,
僕は歌い 橋をかけよう
I will sing and build a bridge,
だからサイレン 鳴らすためと どこまでも片側に沿ったリズム 過ぎた街並は終の愛と遠くへ
so a siren to ring, a rhythm along one side forever, past cityscape far away with final love.
伝えられない歪みかけのイメージに 目が覚めた抵抗 型落ちの衝動
To the uncommunicable distorted image, awakened resistance, outdated impulse,
砕けたcry & dream 扉だけの理想 街が雑音に溺れしゃがれても
shattered cry & dream, sole ideal of a door, even if the city drowns in noise and grows husky,
僕は歌い 舵を捨てよう
I will sing and throw away the rudder,
だからサイレン 響くためと 響くためと
so a siren to echo, to echo.
Don't be afraid daybreak has come
Let it all out, Let it all out
強がってなくてもいいんだね
it's okay not to act tough, right?
誰かが描いていた 壁の落書きの花が 揺れる
The graffiti flower on the wall that someone painted is swaying.
自分らしさなんて 誰もわからないよ
Nobody knows what being oneself is.
長い長い道の途中で 失くしたり拾ったり
On this long, long road, losing and picking things up,
急に寂しくなって 泣いちゃう日もあるけれど
sometimes suddenly feeling lonely and crying, but...
涙も痛みも星に変えよう 明日を照らす 灯をともそう
Let's turn tears and pain into stars, let's light a lamp to illuminate tomorrow.
小さく迷ってても ふたりで作ろう
Even if we wander a little, let's make it together,
星屑を 強く光る 永遠を探そう
stardust, searching for an eternity that shines brightly.
Let it all out, Let it all out
足りないことだらけだね
it's full of things we lack, isn't it?
足りなくていいんだね だから君と出会えたんだ
It's okay to lack them, that's why I was able to meet you.
「確か」が何なのか それが知りたくて
Wanting to know what "certainty" is,
小さなナイフを 靴下に隠していた
I was hiding a small knife in my sock.
強がってついた 嘘の方がずっと痛かった
The lie I told while acting tough always hurt much more.
本当は 恐いけれど 生きていく
It's truly frightening, but we live on.
笑顔の君を 風が撫でていく
The wind caresses your smiling face.
小さな手かざして ふたりで作ろう
Holding out small hands, let's make it together,
星屑を 強く光る 永遠を探そう
stardust, searching for an eternity that shines brightly.
正しいことが 間違ってたら どうすればいい?
What should I do if what's right was wrong?
悲しいことが 正しかったら 受け入れるだけ?
If sadness was what's right, should I just accept it?
失くしたと思ってた でも君が知っていた
I thought I had lost it, but you knew.
君がいて本当に良かった
I'm so glad you were here.
涙も 痛みも 星に変えよう 明日を照らす 灯をともそう
Let's turn tears and pain into stars, let's light a lamp to illuminate tomorrow.
小さく迷ってても 歩いていく 君と歩いていく
Even if we wander a little, I'll walk, I'll walk with you.
それだけは変わらないでいようね
Let's make sure that's the only thing that never changes.
スペースシップ
Spaceship,
僕を置いてって
leaving me behind,
誰もいなくなった
no one was left,
星に落ちた羽翼を
dropping feathers onto a star.
スペースシップ
Spaceship,
僕ら間違うた
we were wrong,
抱きしめたかった
I wanted to hold you tight.
息もできない夜に流星を見た
I saw a shooting star on a breathless night.
引力に似た感情の下降
A descent of emotion resembling gravity,
この身と引き換えの思い出に触れてくれないか
won't you touch the memories traded for this body?
壊してくれ
Break it
その腕で
with those arms,
何度でも名を呼んで
calling my name over and over.
フラッシュバックで
In a flashback,
in a flashback,
もういっそ何も見えない僕は
I can no longer see anything at all.
知らなかった
I didn't know,
知りたかった
I wanted to know
君の笑顔、湧き出す場所で
the place where your smile springs forth.
ブラックボックスで
In the black box,
in the black box,
触れるあと僅かな距離が遠い
the distance left to touch is so far away.
あらゆる悲しみは星を目指す
All kinds of sadness aim for the stars.
スペースシップ
Spaceship,
無音が痛いよ
the silence hurts.
できれば笑って
If possible, smile
何でもないさようならを
and say a casual goodbye.
スペースシップ
Spaceship,
今日も間違えた
I got it wrong again today,
運命を変えて
changing fate.
なりふり構わぬ手口で全部消えても
Even if everything disappears, losing my way...
貴方は風のように
Like the wind, you
目を閉じては夕暮れ 何を考えているんだろうか
close your eyes in the twilight, I wonder what you're thinking.
目蓋を開いていた
With your eyelids open,
貴方の目はビードロ
your eyes are like glass.
少しだけ晴れの匂いがした
There was a faint scent of clearing.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom!
咲いて晴れのせい
Blossom for the sake of clearing!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
胸を打つ音よ響け
The sound that strikes the heart, oh resonate,
僕ら晴る風
we are the clearing wind!
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠く、まだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away!
晴れに晴れ、晴れ晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up, clear skies, flowers bloom!
咲いて晴れのせい
Blossom for the sake of clearing!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
降りしきる雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even in the pouring rain, above the clouds it's clear.
土を打つ音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
The sound hitting the ground, resonate, we are the spring storm!
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠く、まだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away!
通り雨草を撫で 羊雲 あれも春のせい
A passing shower, swaying grass, cumulus clouds, also spring's doing.
風のように胸に春乗せ 晴るを待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring in our chests, waiting for clearing.
晴れに晴れ、空よ裂け 裂いて春のせい
Clear up, sky, tear open, tear open for spring's sake!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
胸を打つ音奏で 僕ら春風
Playing the sound that strikes the heart, we are the spring breeze!
音に聞く晴るの風 さぁこの歌よ響け
Listen to the sound of the clearing wind, now let this song resonate!
貴方は晴れのように 目を閉じては青色
Like fair weather, you close your eyes to the blue.
何が悲しいのだろうか 目蓋を開いている
What is making you sad? With your eyelids open.
貴方の目にビードロ 今少し雨の匂いがした
Now there's a little scent of rain in your eyes.
泣きに泣き、空よ泣き 泣いて雨のせい
Cry, oh sky, weep, weep because of the rain!
降り頻る雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even in the frequent rain, above the clouds it's clearing.
土を打つ音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
The sound hitting the ground, resonate, we are the stormy spring!
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠く、まだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away!
通り雨草を撫で 羊雲 あれも春のせい
A passing shower, swaying grass, cumulus clouds, also spring's doing.
晴れに晴れだけ空よだけ 晴れに晴れのせい
Clear up, clear up, sky clear up, for the sake of clear skies!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
降りしきる雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even in the pouring rain, above the clouds it's clear.
土を打つ音よ鳴れ 僕ら春風
The sound hitting the ground, resonate, we are the spring breeze!
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠く、まだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away!
土を打つ音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
The sound hitting the ground, resonate, we are the stormy spring!
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠く、まだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away!
通り雨草を撫で 羊雲 あれも春のせい
A passing shower, swaying grass, cumulus clouds, also spring's doing.
風のように胸に春乗せ 晴るを待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring in our chests, waiting for clearing.
晴れに晴れ、晴レ空ヨ、咲け
Clear up, clear skies, bloom!
咲いて春のせい
Blossom for spring's sake!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
小さな頃には
When I was small,
宝の地図が頭の中に
a treasure map was in my mind,
浮かんでいて
floating within my head.
いつでも探してた奇跡の場所を
Always searching for that miraculous place,
知らない誰かに負けないように
so as not to lose to someone I don't know.
今ではほこりだらけの毎日
Now, every day is covered in dust.
いつの日かすべての
Someday, I'll surrender myself
時に身を委ねるだけ
to the flow of all time.
もしも世界が変わるのなら
If the world is going to change,
何も知らない頃の私に
take me back to when I knew nothing,
連れていって思い出が色あせないように
so my memories won't fade away.
小さな頃から歌を歌って
Singing songs since I was small,
夢見る心温めてた
warming my dreaming heart.
みんなで真似した秘密のメロディ
The secret melody everyone copied,
今度は上手く聴こえるように
so it can be heard better this time.
今ではため息ついてばかりで
Now, I just keep sighing away,
誰もまだ本当の夢さえつかめないまま
still unable to grasp a true dream.
もしも時代が戻るのなら
If the era could turn back,
涙を知った頃の私に
take me to myself who knew tears,
連れていってせつなさが追いかけないように
so loneliness won't catch up to me.
もしも世界が変わるのなら
If the world is going to change,
何も知らない頃の私に
take me back to when I knew nothing,
連れていって思い出が色あせないように
so my memories won't fade away.
もしも世界が変わるのなら
If the world is going to change,
何も知らない頃の私に
take me back to when I knew nothing,
連れていって思い出が色あせないように
so my memories won't fade away,
連れていってせつなさが追いかけないように
and loneliness won't catch up to me.
ぼくらのレットイットビー
Lyrics・Music：針原翼（はりーP）
Bokura no Let It Be
Lyrics & Music: Harry-P
生まれ変われるのなら
If we could be reborn once again,
目印になるから巻いておこう
I'll tie a marker so we won't lose our way.
小指と小指の長い糸 ほどけない様に結んどこう
A long string tied around our pinkies, bound so it won't untangle.
夏祭り りんご飴 雨降り空に
Summer festivals, candy apples, in the rainy sky
虹が架かる頃なのだから
when a rainbow arches across,
壊れた感情が いつか 君を消していく
Someday, broken emotions will make you fade away,
見えなくなると 失われる灯火
and as you disappear, the light is lost.
でも 結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちてないから
But the long string tied between us hasn't frayed apart,
また ぼくたちは 出会う時が来る
so I'm sure the time for us to meet again will come.
きっと
Surely...
ぼくら おとなになったら
When we grow up into adults,
正義のヒーローになるんだ
we'll become heroes of justice,
地球の平和を守るのさ
protecting the peace of the earth.
探検しようぜ おばけ屋敷
Let's explore the haunted house,
でも 本当は 怖くて
even though we're actually scared,
泣き虫 一緒にいたいだけ
like crybabies who just want to stay together.
明日も晴れて空を 青く照らせば
If tomorrow is sunny and lights the sky in blue,
ぼくらは ここにひみつきちを作ろう
let's build our secret base right here.
そして探検しよう 雨ならゲームをしよう
And let's explore, or play games if it rains.
そんな時間が ずっと続くはずだったんだ
Such time was supposed to last forever.
そう 悪者は ぼくだった
Yes, the villain was me.
逃げたのは ぼくだった
The one who ran away was me.
嘘じゃない 本当の嘘つきだ
It's no lie, I'm a true liar.
生まれ変われるのなら 目印になるから 巻いておこう
If I'm ever reborn, I'll tie a mark so we won't lose it.
小指と小指の長い糸 ほぐれない様に 結んでこう
Let's tie our pinkies together with a long thread so it won't untangle.
夏祭り りんご飴 雨降り空に 虹がかかる 頃なのに
Even though it was time for summer festivals, candy apples, and rainbows over rainy skies,
壊れた感情が いつか 君を消していく
broken emotions will eventually make you fade away.
見えなくなる前に 眠っていたんだ
Before you disappeared, you were sleeping peacefully.
でも 結んだ長い糸 ほぐれ落ちて いないから
But the long thread we tied hasn't frayed and fallen apart,
また ぼくたちは 出会う時間が来る きっと
so surely, the time will come for us to meet again.
ぼくら おとなになったら せいぎのヒーローになるんだよ
When we grow up, we'll become heroes of justice.
呼んで！
Call out!
やるの？ マシュマロ？
Are we doing it? Marshmallows?
I heard marshmallows.
マシュマロ？ マシュマロだって！？
Marshmallows? Did you say marshmallows?!
マシュマロだって！ マシュマロだって！
Marshmallows! Marshmallows!
マシュマロだー！ やったー！
It's marshmallows! Yay!
マシュマロ！
Marshmallows!
食べたいの？ 食べたい！ いえーい！
You wanna eat them? I want some! Yay!
マイスイートマシュマロ！
My sweet marshmallow!
イエイ！ イエイ！ イエイ！ マシュマロパーティー！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Marshmallow party!
マシュマロパーティー！
Marshmallow party!
乾杯！ 乾杯！ 乾杯！
Cheers! Cheers! Cheers!
マシュマロ！マシュマロ！マシュマロ！マシュマロ！
Marshmallow! Marshmallow! Marshmallow! Marshmallow!
Let's go!
はい！ はい！ 火をつけて！
Yes! Yes! Light the fire!
焼いてる？マシュマロ？
Are you roasting marshmallows?
はいはい！
Yes, yes!
I'm amazing at it. Yeah?
素晴らしい！
That's amazing!
燃えろよ燃えろ 燃えろよ燃えろ
Burn, burn, burn, burn!
焼けるんじゃない？焼くんじゃない？
Aren't we roasting them? Aren't we roasting them?
ほい！ほい！ほい！
Hoi! Hoi! Hoi!
What is this?
This is perfection!
Perfect! 焦げ焦げじゃない？
Perfect! Isn't it burnt?
食べますか！いただきます！美味しい！
Shall we eat? Itadakimasu! Delicious!
あ、美味しい？美味しい？
Oh, is it good? Good?
How's your trip? Very spooky.
ちょうどいい！
Just right!
美味しい！
Delicious!
美味しい？美味しい！
Good? Delicious!
星空に願いを 星に願いを！
Make a wish upon the starry sky, a wish upon a star!
一緒に！ 歌おう、歌うの！
Together! Let's sing, sing a song!
イエイ！ イエイ！ イエイ！ イエイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
追いかけても
Chasing,
chasing,
届かない雲のような
like an unreachable cloud,
言葉で表せない
feelings that cannot be expressed
感情 見つけたよ
in words, I found them.
胸の中でざわめいてる 波の本当の意味を
The true meaning of the stirring waves inside my chest
日差しに遮られて 私はまだ知らない
obscured by the sunlight, I still don't know.
あの頃描いた 絵日記みたい
Like a picture diary I drew back then,
すべてが色付き始める、ほら
everything begins to color, look!
真夏の空と海の青さに
In the blue of the midsummer sky and sea,
眩しくて目を閉じても
even if I close my eyes, dazzled,
わたしの心の端っこを
the corner of my heart
掴んで離さない 君の声は
your voice, which grabs and won't let go,
これが「恋」かな
I wonder if this is "love".
自転車 押し 歩く 君 の 隣 で その 横顔
Walking alongside you as you push your bicycle, gazing at your profile
そっと 見つめ て いる と 呼吸 を 忘れてしまう
when I softly gaze at you, I forget to breathe.
子どもの頃 見 た 万華鏡 の よう
Like a kaleidoscope I saw as a child,
明日 が 来る来る 変わり て いく 、 ほら
tomorrow keeps changing and spinning, look!
真夏の太陽に 照らされて 焼き付くような痛みも
Illuminated by the midsummer sun, the burning pain...
うれしさも切なさも全部 初めて出会う大切な気持ち
All the happiness and sadness, precious feelings for the first time,
なくしたくない
I don't want to lose them.
どうしてだろう もっと知りたい 君のことも自分のことも
Why is it? I want to know more about you and about myself.
真夏の空と海の青さに 眩しくて目を閉じても
Even if I close my eyes, dazzled by the blue of the midsummer sky and sea,
わたしの心の端っこを 掴んで離さない 君の声は
your voice, which grabs and won't let go of the corner of my heart,
優しく 響く
resounds gently.
そして、 恋 が 始まる
And then, love begins.
真夏の空と海の青さに
In the blue of the midsummer sky and sea,
眩しくて
dazzling,
目を閉じても
even if I close my eyes,
わたしの心の端っこを
the corner of my heart
掴んで離さない 君の声は
your voice, which grabs and won't let go,
やさしく響く
resounds gently.
恋が始まる
Love begins.
The other day, I met a bear,
A great big bear, away up there!
The other day,
I met a bear,
A great big bear,
Away up there!
The other day I met a bear,
A great big bear away up there.
He looked at me, I looked at him,
He sized up me, I sized up him.
He said to me, "Why don't you run?
I see you don't have any gun."
And so I ran away from there,
And right behind me was that bear.
Ahead of me, I saw a tree,
A great big tree, oh, golly gee!
The lowest branch was ten feet up,
I had to jump and trust my luck.
And so I jumped into the air,
And missed that branch away up there.
Now don't you fret and don't you frown,
I caught that branch on the way back down.
That's all there is, there is no more,
Until I meet that bear once more.
The other day,
I met a bear,
A great big bear,
Away up there!
The other day I met a bear,
A great big bear away up there.
The other day,
I met a bear,
A great big bear,
Away up there!
The other day I met a bear,
A great big bear away up there.
He looked at me, I looked at him,
He sized up me, I sized up him.
He said to me, "Why don't you run?
I see you don't have any gun."
And so I ran away from there,
And right behind me was that bear.
Ahead of me, I saw a tree,
A great big tree, oh, golly gee!
The lowest branch was ten feet up,
I had to jump and trust my luck.
And so I jumped into the air,
And missed that branch away up there.
Now don't you fret and don't you frown,
I caught that branch on the way back down.
That's all there is, there is no more,
Until I meet that bear once more.
The end, the end, the end,
The end, the end, the end!
小さな冒険者
Chisana Boukensha
Lyrics・Music:佐藤良成
Lyrics & Music: Ryosei Sato
転んで擦りむいたとこ
I fell down and grazed myself,
血がにじんでしみるけれど
blood oozes and is seeping through.
へっちゃらさすぐ治るから
I'll just leave it alone because it'll heal soon,
明日にはかさぶたできる
tomorrow I will have a scab.
今日もまたバカにされたよ
Today again I was treated like a fool,
悔しいけれど
it was embarrassing and frustrating, but
今に笑い返してやる
I'll laugh it off for now.
岬から船を出せば
If you sail a ship from a cape,
風を受け帆が膨らむ
the sail will swell out in the wind.
ぼくは今土を離れ
At this moment I part with the land
七つの海を股にかける
and travel the seven seas.
ケンカして殴られたとこ紫アザになった
Got in a fight and where I was struck became a purple bruise,
へっちゃらさ今日のところは負けにことにしておいてやる
I'm just gonna concede defeat for today.
丘に立ち手を広げて
Standing on a hill I spread my arms
風を待ち羽ばたくのさ
and flap against the wind.
ぼくは今土を離れ
At this moment I part with the land,
大空渡る一羽の鳥
as a bird crossing the enormous sky.
転んで 擦りむいたとこ 血がにじんで しみるけれど
I fell down and grazed myself, blood oozes and is seeping through, but
へっちゃらさ すぐ治るから 明日にはかさぶたできる
I'll just leave it alone because it'll heal pretty soon, tomorrow I will have a scab
今日もまた バカにされたよ 恥ずかしいし 悔しいけれど
Today again I was treated like a fool, it was embarrassing and frustrating, but
へっちゃらさ 覚えておけよ 今に見返しといてやる
I'll just leave it, but hey don't you forget, for now I shall return a smile
岬から 船を出せば 風を受け 帆がふくらむ
If you sail a ship from a cape, the sail will swell out in the wind
ぼくは今 土を離れ 七つの海を 股にかける
At this moment I part with the land, and travel the seven seas
ケンカして 殴られたところ 紫 アザになった
Got in a fight and where I was struck, became a purple bruise
へっちゃらさ 今のところは 負けたことにしといてやる
I'm just gonna leave it at that for today, and concede defeat
丘に立ち 手を広げて 風を待ち 羽ばたくのさ
Standing on a hill I spread my arms, and flap against the wind
ぼくは今 土を離れ 大空渡る 一羽の鳥
At this moment I part with the land, as a bird crossing the enormous sky
南から 風が吹いて 急に雨 降りはじめた
The wind blows from the south, and rain comes falling all of a sudden
春はすぐ 隣にいる 洗濯物 取り込まなくちゃ
Spring is right around the corner, I have to bring in all the laundry
Oh hi everybody! I hope that you have enjoyed this beautiful night.
Morning is so far. I think you know what time it is now.
Time to pull out the number one businesswoman of Hololive English.
Oh hi, I am Nanashi Mumei from Hololive English Promise.
This is the part of the stream where I tell you about the birthday merchandise.
I will show you now, over here. こちら。
I will show you now, over here. Here.
My birthday merchandise is the camp! Seemed who could have assumed this?
My birthday merchandise is the camp! Who could have assumed this?
Uh I instead of reading this here, which I could totally do, let's just go ahead and show you the first thing. Next, our first is こちら。
Instead of reading this here, which I could totally do, let's just go show you the first thing. Next, our first is here.
Here we have a campin' tapestry. That is right, it's a tapestry of me, Mumei.
Campin' for you, for your wall, make way if your walls are covered in things.
If your wall is empty, you are so welcome. Uh it's a B2 size tapestry.
If your wall is empty, you are so welcome. It's a B2 size tapestry.
Um I think I really like the art. It's super, super pretty.
I think I really like the art. It's super, super pretty.
And I don't know, maybe it can inspire you to go outside and look at the stars, or maybe it can make you grateful that you have a roof over your head.
There's a lot, lots of things you can do with this.
Uh maybe next up is... こちら. A hat, a cap, a MOOM cap.
Maybe next up is... here. A hat, a cap, a MOOM cap.
Called this because it says MOOM on it. What else is there?
There is a little owl face. Do you see that? Do you see that in the MOOM?
It has my feathers. You can really tell it's MOOM.
Yeah, uh I don't know, I feel like caps are pretty nice, pretty useful. You wear them on your head. You can wear them in whatever direction you so please.
Yeah, I feel like caps are pretty nice, pretty useful. You wear them on your head. You can wear them in whatever direction you so please.
Uh yeah, really up to you. You have a lot of freedom with this one.
Yeah, really up to you. You have a lot of freedom with this one.
Uh next is... こちら. It's a compact wa-- I I forgot I named it that. It It is. It is a compact wall...
Next is... here. It's a compact wa-- I forgot I named it that. It is. It is a compact wall...
Uh yeah. Uh do we still use wallets today? I guess we do. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, you can put uh money, cards, coins if you still use those for some reason.
Do we still use wallets today? I guess we do. Yeah, you can put money, cards, coins if you still use those for some reason.
Or uh oh, pro tip. Pro tip from me, Nanashi Mumei, the number one businesswoman of Hololive English, maybe even Hololive I should probably shouldn't say that.
Or oh, pro tip. Pro tip from me, Nanashi Mumei, the number one businesswoman of Hololive English, maybe even Hololive—I probably shouldn't say that.
Uh you can also use it for the money that you can save from combining your purchase, bundling it with other merchandise, which will reduce the shipping cost, pro tip. I I said this already. Just just just a little advice, just just just putting that out there.
You can also use it for the money that you can save from combining your purchase, bundling it with other merchandise, which will reduce the shipping cost, pro tip. I said this already. Just a little advice, just putting that out there.
Uh yeah, nice wallet for money. Next up is...
Yeah, nice wallet for money. Next up is...
こちら
Here is...
Mumei's Guitar Pick Keychain.
That's right. You can get one of the thousands of guitar picks
that I own that is like the one that I use today
in this live playing guitar.
Oh, yeah. So you can actually remove the pick from the keychain
and use it to play-- play guitar.
and use it to play—play guitar.
Or maybe use it for your-- like, you could use it as a toothpick maybe, I don't know, maybe thin enough.
Or maybe use it as a toothpick maybe, I don't know, maybe thin enough.
Depends how big the gaps in your teeth are.
Um, yeah. Functional pick!
Real pick!
Nice. Picks are nice.
And then finally is...
The bonus, the bonus item, we have a polaroid again this year.
The bonus item, we have a polaroid again this year.
And like always, there is a limited one.
If you buy the full set, you can get a truly signed Nanashi Mumei polaroid.
Uh, but do not fret if you are not able to get the limited set, you can get a printed signature of mine, me, Nanashi Mumei.
But do not fret if you are not able to get the limited set, you can get a printed signature of mine, me, Nanashi Mumei.
Uh, yeah. Uh, this is if you buy the full set.
This is if you buy the full set.
If you want this.
And this is everything all together. Oh, it's so pleasing to look at, the when it's in a in a set.
And this is everything all together. Oh, it's so pleasing to look at when it's in a set.
Yes, that's the word, a set, complete set.
Like this. Yes, hopefully there's something you like, something you could use, useful for you, something you can enjoy and cherish.
Yes. Anyways,  it will be available as soon as the live ends.
Yes. Anyways, it will be available as soon as the live ends.
So really  pay attention. Pay attention to when I am gone out of here.
So really pay attention. Pay attention to when I am gone out of here.
Ah, anyways,  I pulled an all-nighter, didn't I? The  sun is rising in the east.
Ah, anyways, I've pulled an all-nighter, didn't I? The sun is rising in the east.
I think I got  one more song left in me before I have to  crash into that tent there.
I think I got one more song left in me before I have to crash into that tent there.
Are you guys holding up?  Good for one more song?
Are you guys holding up? Good for one more song?
Yeah, you are.  All right, all right. Let's get, let me get ready and hopefully, yeah, not take too much time. Okay, okay. I'll get ready.
Yeah, you are. All right, all right. Let's get—let me get ready and hopefully, yeah, not take too much time. Okay, okay. I'll get ready.
遠い、遠い、
Far, far away,
笑えない話。
it's no laughing story.
いつか、ぼくが居なくなったなら
Someday, if I were to disappear,
深い、深い森に落ちた
Having fallen into a deep, deep forest,
きみは一人で行くんだぜ。
You must go there alone.
繋いだ手には柔らかな体温
In tied hands, there is a soft body heat,
握った指が、ゆるり、ほどけたら。
And fingers which held it untied loosely.
枯れた音色の鐘が鳴る。
Bells of a dry tone are ringing.
きみは一人で行くんだぜ。
You must go there alone.
そのまま二人歩んで、一人。
As we are, the two of us walk alone.
嘘付く声も、もう絶え絶えに
The lying voice is quite broken.
うつむき、二人。影が一つ
The two of us downcast, there is one shadow.
ぼくも独りで行くんだぜ?
I must go alone there as well, you know?
きみは淡い恋に落ちた
You have fallen in a faint love.
高い高い崖に咲く花
Blooming flowers on a tall, tall cliff.
「届かないな。」わかっているくせに。
"I can't seem to reach it," though you already know.
今度は一人で行くんだぜ。
Next time, you must go there alone.
それから一人歩いて独り
Since then I have walked alone, been solitary,
嘘付く事も、もう疲れた。
And gotten tired of lying.
うつむき独り 黄金の部屋
I am downcast alone, in a golden room,
きみとふたりでいたんだぜ
I used to stay with you there.
遠い、遠い、笑えない話。
Far away, far away, a tale without a smile.
いつか、ぼくが居なくなったなら
Someday, if I were to disappear,
深い、深い森に落ちた
I fell deep into the deep forest.
きみは一人で行くんだぜ。
You will go on alone.
繋いだ手には柔らかな体温
In our clasped hands, a gentle warmth.
握った指が、ゆるり、ほどけたら。
When our intertwined fingers slowly untangled.
枯れた音色の鐘が鳴る。
A bell with a withered tone rings.
きみは一人で行くんだぜ。
You will go on alone.
そのままで二人歩いて、一人
Walking together like that, then alone,
嘘付く声も、もう絶え絶えに。
Even the lying voice is now barely hanging on.
うつむき二人影がひとつ
Two downcast shadows become one.
ぼくも独りで行くんだぜ？
Will I also go on alone?
きみは淡い恋に落ちた。
You fell into a fleeting love.
高い高い崖に咲く花。
A flower blooming on a high, high cliff.
「届かないな。」
"I can't reach it,"
わかっているくせに。
even though you know that.
ぼくは深い森に落ちた
I fell deep into the forest.
黒くすすけて汚れた果実
A fruit blackened and stained with soot.
それで終わりそれだけの話
That's the end, that's all there is to it.
きみは、ひとりで行くんだぜ。
You will go on alone.
それから一人歩いて独り
Then walking alone, all by yourself,
嘘付く事も、もう疲れた。
Tired of lying as well.
うつむき独り黄金の部屋
Looking down alone in the golden room,
きみとふたりでいたんだぜ
Where you and I were together.
遠い、遠い、笑えない話。
Far away, far away, a tale without a smile.
いつか、ぼくが居なくなったなら
Someday, if I were to disappear,
深い、深い森に落ちた
I fell deep into the deep forest.
きみは一人で行くんだぜ。
You will go on alone.
遠い、遠い、笑えない話。
Far away, far away, a tale without a smile.
いつか、ぼくが居なくなったなら
Someday, if I were to disappear,
深い、深い森に落ちた
I fell deep into the deep forest.
きみは
You...